ichess.net 2019-07-19

# iChess LLC Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy - iChess.net

**iChess LLC**

**_Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy_**

**Updated: May 5, 2018** ** **

We have updated our Privacy and Cookie Policies to be clear, transparent and GDPR compliant. 

We go into detail on what we do, don’t do and why on the rest of this page but for those who just want a brief summary, here it is:

**Personal Data**

  * We, iChess LLC, collect personal data to process purchases and market our goods and services.
  * We collect email addresses, names, chess skill level and sometimes billing and shipping addresses and country of residence. We only collect this data when it is entered into a form on our website. 
  * Our lawful basis for collecting this information is that it is necessary for us to fulfill orders, deliver downloads and send relevant information and offers to our customers and email subscribers. Anyone can unsubscribe at any time either by a) clicking the “unsubscribe” button at the bottom of any email they receive from us, or b) requesting we remove them from our system by emailing CustService@iChess.net
  * This data will be shared with InfusionSoft, our email marketing platform and a data processor. We use InfusionSoft to store contact information and manage our marketing campaigns.
  * This data will only be kept as long as it is needed. If the data subject requests we remove their data, we will. If we see that a person is no longer opening our emails, we will remove them from our systems within 6 months. All contact data belonging to people who have unsubscribed will be removed within 1 month.
  * If you have a complaint, please email CustService@iChess.net.

**Cookies**

We use cookies on iChess.net to:

  * Show you adverts on Facebook, Instagram and the Google Display Network.
  * Help us understand our website visitors better with Google Analytics

If you do not accept and agree with this Privacy Policy, you must stop using Our Site (www.iChess.net)  immediately.

**Background:**

iChess LLC understands that your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your information is used and shared online. We respect and value the privacy of everyone who visits Our Site and will only collect and use information in ways that are useful to you and in a manner consistent with your rights and Our obligations under the law.

This Policy applies to Our use of any and all data collected by us in relation to your use of Our Site. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and ensure that you understand it.

Your acceptance of Our Privacy Policy is deemed to occur upon your first use of Our Site. ** **

If you do not accept and agree with this Privacy Policy, you must stop using Our Site immediately.

  1. **Definitions and Interpretation**

In this Policy the following terms shall have the following meanings: 

**“Account”** | means an account required to access and/or use certain areas and features of Our Site;  
---|---  
**“Cookie”** | means a small text file placed on your computer or device by Our Site when you visit certain parts of Our Site and/or when you use certain features of Our Site. Details of the Cookies used by Our Site are set out in section 12, below;]  
**“Our Site”** | means this website, **iChess.net.**  
**“EU Cookie Law”** | means the relevant parts of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 as amended in 2004, 2011 and 2015.  
**“We/Us/Our”** | means **iChess LLC** , a limited company registered in United States under [ **Insert Company Number** **]** , whose registered address is **2472 Jett Ferry Rd Suite 400-250, Atlanta, Georgia, 30338, United States**.  
  
  2. **Information About Us**
    * Our Site, **iChess.net** is owned and operated by **iChess LLC** a limited company registered in United States whose registered address is **2472 Jett Ferry Rd Suite 400-250, Atlanta, Georgia, 30338, United States**.

  3. **Scope – What Does This Policy Cover?**

This Privacy Policy applies only to your use of Our Site. It does not extend to any websites that are linked to from Our Site (whether We provide those links or whether they are shared by other users). We have no control over how your data is collected, stored or used by other websites and We advise you to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing any data to them.

  4. **What Data Do We Collect?**

Some data will be collected automatically by Our Site for further details, please see section 12 on Our use of Cookies, other data will only be collected if you voluntarily submit it and consent to Us using it for the purposes set out in section 5, for example, when signing up for an Account. Depending upon your use of Our Site, We may collect some or all of the following data:

  * Name
  * Contact information such as email addresses and telephone numbers
  * Demographic information such as post code, preferences and interests
  * Financial information such as credit / debit card numbers
  * IP address (automatically collected)
  * Web browser type and version (automatically collected)
  * Operating system (automatically collected)
  * A list of URLs starting with a referring site, your activity on Our Site, and the site you exit to (automatically collected)

  5. **How Do We Use Your Data?**
    * All personal data is stored securely in accordance with the EU [General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679)](https://uk.practicallaw.thomsonreuters.com/PLCCoreDocument/ViewDocument.html?navId=AACF20BB9BED7DE45F3549371482B6BD&comp=pluk&DocumentGuid=Ie887bae554de11e698dc8b09b4f043e0&ViewType=FullText&HasDraftingNotes=False&ResearchReportViewMode=False&SessionScopeIsValid=True&IsCourtWireDocument=False&IsSuperPrivateDocument=False&IsPrivateDocument=False&ClientMatter=Cobalt.Website.Platform.Web.UserData.ClientMatter&AuthenticationStrength=5&IsMedLitStubDocument=False&IsOutOfPlanDocumentViewClicked=False&TransitionType=Default&ContextData=\(sc.Default\)&BillingContextData=\(sc.Default\)) (GDPR). For more details on security see section 6, below.
    * We use your data to provide the best possible products and services to you. This includes:
      * Providing and managing your Account
      * Providing and managing your access to Our Site
      * Supplying Our products and services to you
      * Personalising and tailoring Our products and services for you
      * Responding to communications from you
      * Supplying you with email promotions and newsletters that you have subscribed to (you may unsubscribe or opt-out at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of these emails).
    * In some cases, the collection of data may be a statutory or contractual requirement, and We will be limited in the products and services We can provide you without your consent for Us to be able to use such data.
    * With your permission and/or where permitted by law, We may also use your data for marketing purposes which may include contacting you by email and/or post with information, news and offers on Our products and/or services **.** We will not, however, send you any unsolicited marketing or spam and will take all reasonable steps to ensure that We fully protect your rights and comply with Our obligations under the GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, as amended in 2004, 2011 and 2015.
    * Under GDPR we will ensure that your personal data is processed lawfully, fairly, and transparently, without adversely affecting your rights. We will only process your personal data if at least one of the following basis applies:
      1. you have given consent to the processing of your personal data for one or more specific purposes;
      2. processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or in order to take steps at the request of you prior to entering into a contract;
      3. processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject;
      4. processing is necessary to protect the vital interests of you or of another natural person;
      5. processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller; and/or
      6. processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject which require protection of personal data, in particular where the data subject is a child.

  6. **How and Where Do We Store Your Data?**
    * We only keep your data for as long as We need to in order to use it as described above in section 5, and/or for as long as We have your permission to keep it. In any event, We will conduct an annual review to ascertain whether we need to keep your data. Your data will be deleted if we no longer need it in accordance with the terms of our Data Retention Policy. Our Data Retention Policies are:

To remove all data related to persons who have either not provided or withdrawn consent for us to contact them.

  * Some or all of your data may be stored or transferred outside of the European Economic Area (“the EEA”) (The EEA consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein). You are deemed to accept and agree to this by using Our Site and submitting information to Us. We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated as safely and securely as it would be within the EEA and under the GDPR. Such steps may include, but not be limited to, the use of legally binding contractual terms between Us and any third parties We engage and the use of the EU-approved Model Contractual Arrangements.
  * Data security is of great importance to Us, and to protect your data We employ commercially reasonable security measures to protect data and seek to partner with companies which do the same.
  * Notwithstanding the security measures that We take, we cannot guarantee the security of any information transmitted to or from the Website, and are not responsible for the actions of any third parties that may receive any such information.

  7. **Do We Share Your Data?**
    * We may contract with third parties to supply products and services to you on Our behalf. These may include payment processing, delivery of goods, search engine facilities, advertising and marketing. In some cases, the third parties may require access to some or all of your data. Where any of your data is required for such a purpose, We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data will be handled safely, securely, and in accordance with your rights, Our obligations, and the obligations of the third party under the law. We currently contract with:

**Infusionsoft:** Identifiable contact details including name and email address.  
**Facebook:** Anonymized data including email address.  
**Google AdWords:** Anonymized data including email address.  
**Google Analytics:** Anonymized data including location, time on site and pages visited.

  * We may compile statistics about the use of Our Site including data on traffic, usage patterns, user numbers, sales and other information. All such data will be anonymised and will not include any personally identifying information. We may from time to time share such data with third parties such as prospective investors, affiliates, partners and advertisers. Data will only be shared and used within the bounds of the law.
  * In certain circumstances We may be legally required to share certain data held by Us, which may include your personal information, for example, where We are involved in legal proceedings, where We are complying with the requirements of legislation, a court order, or a governmental authority. We do not require any further consent from you in order to share your data in such circumstances and will comply as required with any legally binding request that is made of Us.

  8. **What Happens If Our Business Changes Hands?**
    * We may, from time to time, expand or reduce Our business and this may involve the sale and/or the transfer of control of all or part of Our business. Data provided by users will, where it is relevant to any part of Our business so transferred, be transferred along with that part and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this Privacy Policy, be permitted to use the data for the purposes for which it was originally collected by Us.
    * In the event that any of your data is to be transferred in such a manner, you will be contacted in advance and informed of the changes.

  9. **How Can You Control Your Data?**
    * When you submit information via Our Site, you may be given options to restrict Our use of your data. We aim to give you strong controls on Our use of your data (including the ability to opt-out of receiving emails from Us which you may do by unsubscribing using the links provided in Our emails **.**

  10. **Your Right to Withhold Information and Your Right to Withdraw Information After You Have Given it**
    * You may access nearly all Our Site without providing any data at all. However, to access your account on Our Site you may be required to submit or allow for the collection of certain data.
    * You may restrict your internet browser’s use of Cookies. For more information, see section 12.
    * You may withdraw your consent for Us to use your personal data as set out in section 5 at any time by contacting Us using the details set out in section 15, and We will delete Your data from Our systems. However, you acknowledge this may limit Our ability to provide the best possible products and services to you.

  11. **How Can You Access Your Data?**

You have the legal right to ask for a copy of any of your personal data held by Us (where such data is held). Please contact Us for more details at [**Info@iChess.net**](mailto:CustService@iChess.net) or using the contact details below in section 14. ** **

  12. **Cookies and how they Benefit You**

Our website uses cookies, as almost all websites do, to help provide you with the best experience we can. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or mobile phone when you browse websites

**Our cookies help us:**  
• Make our website work as you’d expect  
• Save you having to login every time you visit the site  
• Remember your settings during and between visits  
• Improve the speed/security of the site  
• Allow you to share pages with social networks like Facebook  
• Continuously improve our website for you  
• Make our marketing more efficient (ultimately helping us to offer the service we do at the price we do)

**We do not use cookies to:**  
• Collect any personally identifiable information (without your express permission)  
• Collect any sensitive information (without your express permission)  
• Pass personally identifiable data to third parties  
• Pay sales commissions

You can learn more about all the cookies we use below

**Granting us permission to use cookies**  
If the settings on your software that you are using to view this website (your browser) are adjusted to accept cookies we take this, and your continued use of our website, to mean that you are fine with this. Should you wish to remove or not use cookies from our site you can learn how to do this below, however doing so will likely mean that our site will not work as you would expect.

**Website Function Cookies**  
**Our own cookies**

We use cookies to make our website work including:  
• Making our shopping basket and checkout work  
• Determining if you are logged in or not  
• Remembering your search settings  
• Allowing you to add comments to our site  
• Remembering if we have already asked you certain questions (e.g. you declined to use our app or take our survey)  
There is no way to prevent these cookies being set other than to not use our site.

**Third party functions**  
Our site, like most websites, includes functionality provided by third parties. A common example is an embedded YouTube video. Our site includes the following which use cookies:  
**YouTube embedded video**

Disabling these cookies will likely break the functions offered by these third parties.

**Social Website Cookies**  
We do not use social sharing buttons on our site.

**Anonymous Visitor Statistics Cookies**  
We use cookies to compile visitor statistics such as how many people have visited our website, what type of technology they are using (e.g. Mac or Windows which helps to identify when our site isn’t working as it should for particular technologies), how long they spend on the site, what page they look at etc. This helps us to continuously improve our website. These so called “analytics” programs also tell us if , on an anonymous basis, how people reached this site (e.g. from a search engine) and whether they have been here before helping us to put more money into developing our services for you instead of marketing spend.

We use:  
**Google Analytics**  
**Wicked Reports**

**Advertising Cookies**  
Cookies are widely used in online advertising. Neither us, advertisers or our advertising partners can gain personally identifiable information from these cookies.  
You can learn more about online advertising at http://www.youronlinechoices.com . You can opt-out of almost all advertising cookies at http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices although we would prefer that you didn’t as ultimately adverts help keep much of the internet free. It is also worth noting that opting out of advertising cookies will not mean you won’t see adverts, just simply that they won’t be tailored to you any longer.  
We do not allow advertising cookies on iChess.net.

**Remarketing Cookies**  
You may notice that sometimes after visiting a site you see increased numbers of adverts from the site you visited. This is because advertisers, including ourselves pay for these adverts. The technology to do this is made possible by cookies and as such we may place a so called “remarketing cookie” during your visit. We use these adverts to offer special offers etc to encourage you to come back to our site. Don’t worry we are unable to proactively reach out to you as the whole process is entirely anonymised. You can opt out of these cookies at anytime as explained above.

We use:  
**Google AdWords**  
**Facebook Advertising**

**Turning Cookies Off**  
You can usually switch cookies off by adjusting your browser settings to stop it from accepting cookies (Learn how [here](http://www.attacat.co.uk/resources/cookies/how-to-ban)). Doing so however will likely limit the functionality of our’s and a large proportion of the world’s websites as cookies are a standard part of most modern websites  
It may be that you concerns around cookies relate to so called “spyware”. Rather than switching off cookies in your browser you may find that anti-spyware software achieves the same objective by automatically deleting cookies considered to be invasive. Learn more about [managing cookies with antispyware software](http://www.attacat.co.uk/resources/cookies/how-to-control-your-online-privacy).

  12. **Summary of Your Rights under GDPR**

Under the GDPR, you have:

  * the right to request access to, deletion of or correction of, your personal data held by Us;
  * the right to complain to a supervisory authority;
  * be informed of what data processing is taking place;
  * the right to restrict processing;
  * the right to data portability;
  * object to processing of your personal data;
  * rights with respect to automated decision-making and profiling (see section 14 below).

To enforce any of the foregoing rights or if you have any other questions about Our Site or this Privacy Policy, please contact Us using the details set out in section 15 below.

  13. **Automated Decision-Making and Profiling**

14.1       In the event that We use personal data for the purposes of automated decision-making and those decisions have a legal (or similarly significant effect) on You, You have the right to challenge to such decisions under GDPR, requesting human intervention, expressing their own point of view, and obtaining an explanation of the decision from Us.

 14.2 The right described in section 14.1 does not apply in the following circumstances:

  1. The decision is necessary for the entry into, or performance of, a contract between the You and Us;
  2. The decision is authorised by law; or
  3. You have given you explicit consent.

  * Where We use your personal data for profiling purposes, the following shall apply:
    1. Clear information explaining the profiling will be provided, including its significance and the likely consequences;
    2. Appropriate mathematical or statistical procedures will be used;
    3. Technical and organisational measures necessary to minimise the risk of errors and to enable such errors to be easily corrected shall be implemented; and
    4. All personal data processed for profiling purposes shall be secured in order to prevent discriminatory effects arising out of profiling.
  * We currently make the following automated decisions:

None

14.5 We currently profile your personal data for the following purposes:

None

  14. **Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about Our Site or this Privacy Policy, please contact Us by email at Info@iChess.net by telephone on +1 (678)-400-0625, or by post at **2472 Jett Ferry Rd Suite 400-250, Atlanta, Georgia, 30338, United States**. Please ensure that your query is clear, particularly if it is a request for information about the data We hold about you (as under section 11, above).

  15. **Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy as we may deem necessary from time to time, or as may be required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on Our Site and you will be deemed to have accepted the terms of the Privacy Policy on your first use of Our Site following the alterations. We recommend that you check this page regularly to keep up-to-date.
